Kutay Songül

Ankara, Turkey

kutay2015@gmail.com

github/KutaySong

SUMMARY

Senior engineer with 12+ years of solid experience in managing IT teams and systems, programming languages and full-stack development. A life-long passionate learner and practitioner in various diverse fields which may include music theory, multi-agent evolutionary systems, medicine, biology, cryptology, computer science and data visualization.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineer (10 years)

Aselsan (Ankara)

March 2011 - July 2021

- Administered 6-campus storage systems: Responsible for keeping all confidential corporate data systems secure, fast, up-to-date and accessible with a permissions hierarchy
- Reduced the costs by 100k+ €: Coordinated alone the installment and configuration of RfID print management systems with 1000+ peripherals and 20+ servers and 10+ technical employees. In the pre-purchase process, contacted with alternative international offices to pin out the features the company actually need and thus reduced the costs
- Developed access security check routines, audits, batches, scripts and user intefaces in both ms and linux. Preferred languages were Python, Perl, C#

Software Specialist (2 years)

Turkiye Is Bank (Istanbul)

January 2007 - August 2008

- Increased the online income by 1.000.000+ \$/monthly: Figuring out and reporting a problem in Bank's cluster systems causing a bottleneck in online SGK (insurance) payments. To analyze and data-mine the transaction logs, I preferred the language Perl.
- Developed software for distribution of embedded queue-matic software and updates over 600+ branches.
- Selected as 1st over 400+ candidates in English, talent and intelligence tests and started my career in the IT department after graduating electrical engineering.
- Completed neural networks, pattern recognition and artificial intelligence grad courses in Bosphorus University. Developed C++ and R simulations and codebases for machine learning models.

Research Assistant (2 years)

UNLV Las Vegas (Las Vegas)

August 2018 - January 2020

• Researched renewable energy systems: Designed and simulated a model for civic electrical phase control of interconnected solar panels in Matlab Simulink.

Full Stack Developer (1 year)

Zero Density (İzmir)

August 2021 - January 2022

• Worked on user machine interface for green screen composition software which used Svelte framework on Javascript and Node.js in UI and C++ and unreal engine at back-stage.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Middle East Technical UniversityAnkara, TR

CERTIFICATIONS

Highly Skilled Migrant Programme (UK)

British Consulate General Istanbul

Applied and Accepted for HSMP visa.

2009

SKILLS

Front End: Javascript, CSS; Back End: Python, Scala, Node, Haskell, C/C++

Language Skills: English Toefl:110/120, Toeic:950/990, GMAT:660/800, beginner-level Russian and Spanish

2006

Graduate Courses: Medicine (4 semesters), Cryptology (3 sem.), Machine Learning (4 sem.), Informatics (2 sem.), Renewable Energy (2 sem.), Applied Mathematics (4 sem.)

Hobbies: Youtube education, Piano & guitar & sax player, Sci-fi & Popular science reader, Risk & Chess player, Free-diver (25m)